PT	AU	BA	BE	GP	AF	BF	CA	TI	SO	SE	BS	LA	DT	CT	CY	CL	SP	HO	DE	ID	AB	C1	RP	EM	RI	OI	FU	FX	CR	NR	TC	Z9	U1	U2	PU	PI	PA	SN	EI	BN	J9	JI	PD	PY	VL	IS	PN	SU	SI	MA	BP	EP	AR	DI	D2	EA	EY	PG	WC	SC	GA	UT	PM	OA	HC	HP	DA
J	Rigo, P; Esposito, G; Bornstein, MH; De Pisapia, N; Manzardo, C; Venuti, P				Rigo, Paola; Esposito, Gianluca; Bornstein, Marc H.; De Pisapia, Nicola; Manzardo, Corinna; Venuti, Paola			Brain Processes in Mothers and Nulliparous Women in Response to Cry in Different Situational Contexts: A Default Mode Network Study	PARENTING-SCIENCE AND PRACTICE												Objective: In everyday life, parents must respond to and interact with children while in different situational contexts. How situational contexts influence parents' responses has not been systematically studied. Here we investigated mothers' versus nonmothers' neural responses to infant vocalizations in different situations with different task demands. Design: Using fMRI in 21 women (10 mothers), we explored the effects of being distracted by self-oriented (self-referential decisions about personality adjectives) versus goal-oriented (syllabic counting of personality adjectives) tasks while listening to infant cry in comparison with other emotional sounds (infant laughing, adult crying) on the activity of two medial nodes of the Default Mode Network (DMN): the medial prefrontal cortex (MPFC) and posterior cingulate cortex (PCC). Results: In the self-oriented task while listening to infant cry, both mothers and nulliparas showed (weak) activation of the DMN; this response likely reflects a shift of attention from the task to the cry. In the goal-oriented task, mothers, not nulliparas, showed (weak) activation of the DMN; this result is compatible with interference of emotional sounds while attending to a goal-oriented task, an activity that deactivates the DMN. Conclusions: Mothers are prone to process infant cry and emotional sounds and are less distracted from doing so by situational contexts, demonstrating their greater sensitivity to emotional sounds such as cry. By contrast, situational context influenced brain responses to infant sounds in nulliparas.																	1529-5192	1532-7922				APR 3	2019	19	1-2			SI		69	85		10.1080/15295192.2019.1555430								WOS:000457730500012						
J	Rigo, P; Esposito, G; Bornstein, MH; De Pisapia, N; Venuti, P				Rigo, Paola; Esposito, Gianluca; Bornstein, Marc H.; De Pisapia, Nicola; Venuti, Paola			Self-Cognition and Parental Brain	PARENTING-SCIENCE AND PRACTICE												A key feature of parenting is that it is observable starting from behaviors that are performed daily by adult caregivers during repeated interactions with the child. Functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) research on parental brain should integrate settings that resemble ecologies of situations in which parents typically care for children. However, as our commentators point out, ecological settings in fMRI research are challenging and require a multiperspective approach that systematically considers psychological and behavioral complexities of "mommy brain" to better understand how contingent mental states of mothers articulate with specific multi-tasking situations.																	1529-5192	1532-7922				APR 3	2019	19	1-2			SI		97	100		10.1080/15295192.2019.1556008								WOS:000457730500016						
J	Gui, WJ; Wang, PY; Lei, X; Lin, T; Horta, M; Liu, XY; Yu, J				Gui, Wen-jun; Wang, Peng-yun; Lei, Xu; Lin, Tian; Horta, Marilyn; Liu, Xiao-yi; Yu, Jing			Sleep facilitates consolidation of positive emotional memory in healthy older adults	MEMORY												Evidence has demonstrated that sleep-related memory consolidation declines in ageing. However, little is known about age-related changes to sleep-related emotional memory consolidation, especially when considering the positivity effect observed in older adults. In the present study, we sought to explore whether there is a positive emotional bias in sleep-related memory consolidation among healthy older adults. Young and older adults were randomly assigned either into a sleep or wake condition. All participants encoded positive, negative, and neutral stimuli and underwent recognition tests immediately (test 1), after a 12-hour sleep/wake interval (test 2), and 3 days after test 2 (test 3). Results showed that age-related differences of sleep beneficial effect were modulated by emotion valence. In particular, sleep selectively enhanced positive memory in older adults, while in young adults sleep beneficial effect was manifested in neutral memory. Moreover, the sleep beneficial effect can be maintained at least 3 days in both young and older adults. These findings suggest that older adults had preserved but positive bias of sleep-related memory consolidation, which could be one of the underlying mechanisms for their generally better emotional well-being in daily life. These findings highlight the dynamic interplay among sleep and emotional memory in older adults.																	0965-8211	1464-0686				MAR 16	2019	27	3					387	396		10.1080/09658211.2018.1513038								WOS:000456004400011	30142023					
J	Zhou, C; Yu, M; Tang, XW; Wang, X; Zhang, XB; Zhang, XR; Chen, J				Zhou, Chao; Yu, Miao; Tang, Xiaowei; Wang, Xiang; Zhang, Xiaobin; Zhang, Xiangrong; Chen, Jiu			Convergent and divergent altered patterns of default mode network in deficit and non-deficit schizophrenia	PROGRESS IN NEURO-PSYCHOPHARMACOLOGY & BIOLOGICAL PSYCHIATRY												Objective: Previous studies suggested likely mechanisms underlying the dysfunction of the default mode network (DMN) in schizophrenia. However, altered patterns of the intrinsic activity of the DMN in both deficit schizophrenia (DS) and non-deficit schizophrenia (NDS) patients, as well as the neurocognitive relationships among them, remain unknown. This study explores the resting-state characteristics of the DMN activity in both DS and NDS patients, and further investigates correlations with neurocognitive features. Methods: Demographic, resting-state functional MRI, and neurocognitive data were collected in 37 DS and 38 NDS patients, as well as in 38 matched healthy control subjects (HCs). Independent component analysis was conducted to investigate the characteristics of DMN activity and to further distinguish between common and specific altered regions. In addition, partial correlation analysis was conducted to examine associations between the activity of altered regions and neurocognitive assessments. Results: Overlapping altered brain activity was observed in both DS and NDS patients in the left middle frontal gyrus (MFG), the left angular gyrus (ANG), and the calcarine sulcus (CAL) region. Furthermore, compared to HCs, DS patients showed less activity in the right inferior temporal gyrus, the right para-hippocampal gyrus / hippocampus (PHP / HIP), and the left precuneus (PCUN), while they showed increased activity in the posterior cingulate cortex (PCC). Notably, NDS patients showed less activity in the bilateral middle occipital gyrus. Correlation analysis indicated that, in the DS group, both Trail Making Test (TMT)-B and spatial processing scores were positively associated with the activities of the left PCUN and the right PHP / HIP, while the Stroop color scores were negatively associated with PCC activity. In the NDS group, the TMT-B scores were associated with activities of the left MFG and CAL regions, while the scores of the Wechsler adult intelligence scale (Chinese revision) were negatively associated with CAL region activity. Conclusion: The present study demonstrates convergent and divergent altered patterns of the DMN in both DS and NDS patients. Importantly, the specific altered regions of the DMN in DS patients may be associated with extensive deficient neurocognition, indicating novel insights into the pathogenesis of cognitive impairment in schizophrenia.					Zhou, Chao/0000-0001-6114-0048												0278-5846	1878-4216				MAR 8	2019	89						427	434		10.1016/j.pnpbp.2018.10.012								WOS:000450287400045	30367960					
J	Gotts, SJ; Ramot, M; Jasmin, K; Martin, A				Gotts, Stephen J.; Ramot, Michal; Jasmin, Kyle; Martin, Alex			Altered resting-state dynamics in autism spectrum disorder: Causal to the social impairment?	PROGRESS IN NEURO-PSYCHOPHARMACOLOGY & BIOLOGICAL PSYCHIATRY												Autism spectrum disorder (ASD) is characterized by profound impairments in social abilities and by restricted interests and repetitive behaviors. Much work in the past decade has been dedicated to understanding the brain-bases of ASD, and in the context of resting-state functional connectivity fMRI in high-functioning adolescents and adults, the field has established a set of reliable findings: decreased cortico-cortical interactions among brain regions thought to be engaged in social processing, along with a simultaneous increase in thalamo-cortical and striato-cortical interactions. However, few studies have attempted to manipulate these altered patterns, leading to the question of whether such patterns are actually causally involved in producing the corresponding behavioral impairments. We discuss a few such recent attempts in the domains of fMRI neurofeedback and overt social interaction during scanning, and we conclude that the evidence of causal involvement is somewhat mixed. We highlight the potential role of the thalamus and striatum in ASD and emphasize the need for studies that directly compare scanning during multiple cognitive states in addition to the resting-state.																	0278-5846	1878-4216				MAR 2	2019	90						28	36		10.1016/j.pnpbp.2018.11.002								WOS:000454536600003	30414457					
J	Wu, XR; He, H; Shi, L; Xia, YM; Zuang, KX; Feng, QY; Zhang, Y; Ren, ZT; Wei, DT; Qiu, J				Wu, Xinran; He, Hong; Shi, Liang; Xia, Yunman; Zuang, Kaixiang; Feng, Qiuyang; Zhang, Yao; Ren, Zhiting; Wei, Dongtao; Qiu, Jiang			Personality traits are related with dynamic functional connectivity in major depression disorder: A resting-state analysis	JOURNAL OF AFFECTIVE DISORDERS												Background: Major depressive disorder (MDD) is one of the most well-known psychiatric disorders, which can be destructive for its damage to people's normal cognitive, emotional and social functions. Personality refers to the unique and stable character of thinking and behavior style of an individual, which has long been thought as a key influence factor for MDD. Although some knowledge about the common neural basic between MDD and personality traits has been acquired, there are few studies exploring dynamic neural mechanism behind them, which changes brain connectivity pattern rapidly to adapt to the environment over time. Methods: In this study, the emerging dynamic functional network connectivity (DFNC) method was used in resting-state fMRI data to find the differences between healthy group (N=107) and MDD group (N=109) in state-based dynamic measures, and the correlations between these measures and personality traits (extraversion and neuroticism in Eysenck Personality Questionnaire, EPQ) were explored. Results: The results showed that MDD was significantly less than the health control group in dwell time and fraction time of state 4, which was positively correlated with extraversion score and negatively correlated with neuroticism score. Further exploration on state 4 showed that it had low modularity, hyper-connectedness of sensory-related regions and DMN, and weak connections between cortex and subcortical areas, which suggested that the absence of this state in MDD might represent a decrease in activity and positive emotions. Conclusion: We found the dynamic functional connectivity mechanism underlying MDD, confirmed our hypothesis that there existed the interacted relationship between trait, disease and the brain's dynamic characteristic, and suggested some reference for treatment of depression.																	0165-0327	1573-2517				FEB 15	2019	245						1032	1042		10.1016/j.jad.2018.11.002								WOS:000456697100127	30699845					
J	Zhangr, YQ; Zhang, HL; Nierhaus, T; Pach, D; Witt, CM; Yi, M				Zhangr, Yuqi; Zhang, Haolin; Nierhaus, Till; Pach, Daniel; Witt, Claudia M.; Yi, Ming			Default Mode Network as a Neural Substrate of Acupuncture: Evidence, Challenges and Strategy	FRONTIERS IN NEUROSCIENCE												Acupuncture is widely applied all over the world. Although the neurobiological underpinnings of acupuncture still remain unclear, accumulating evidence indicates significant alteration of brain activities in response to acupuncture. In particular, activities of brain regions in the default mode network (DMN) are modulated by acupuncture. DMN is crucial for maintaining physiological homeostasis and its functional architecture becomes disrupted in various disorders. But how acupuncture modulates brain functions and whether such modulation constitutes core mechanisms of acupuncture treatment are far from clear. This Perspective integrates recent literature on interactions between acupuncture and functional networks including the DMN, and proposes a back-translational research strategy to elucidate brain mechanisms of acupuncture treatment.																	1662-453X					FEB 11	2019	13								100	10.3389/fnins.2019.00100								WOS:000458260100001						
J	Quintana, DS; Rokicki, J; van der Meer, D; Alnaes, D; Kaufmann, T; Cordova-Palomera, A; Dieset, I; Andreassen, OA; Westlye, LT				Quintana, Daniel S.; Rokicki, Jaroslav; van der Meer, Dennis; Alnaes, Dag; Kaufmann, Tobias; Cordova-Palomera, Aldo; Dieset, Ingrid; Andreassen, Ole A.; Westlye, Lars T.			Oxytocin pathway gene networks in the human brain	NATURE COMMUNICATIONS												Oxytocin is a neuropeptide involved in animal and human reproductive and social behavior. Three oxytocin signaling genes have been frequently implicated in human social behavior: OXT (structural gene for oxytocin), OXTR (oxytocin receptor), and CD38 (oxytocin secretion). Here, we characterized the distribution of OXT, OXTR, and CD38 mRNA across the human brain by creating voxel-by-voxel volumetric expression maps, and identified putative gene pathway interactions by comparing gene expression patterns across 20,737 genes. Expression of the three selected oxytocin pathway genes was enriched in subcortical and olfactory regions and there was high co-expression with several dopaminergic and muscarinic acetylcholine genes, reflecting an anatomical basis for critical gene pathway interactions. fMRI meta-analysis revealed that the oxytocin pathway gene maps correspond with the processing of anticipatory, appetitive, and aversive cognitive states. The oxytocin signaling system may interact with dopaminergic and muscarinic acetylcholine signaling to modulate cognitive state processes involved in complex human behaviors.					Andreassen, Ole A./0000-0002-4461-3568; Westlye, Lars T./0000-0001-8644-956X; Quintana, Daniel/0000-0003-2876-0004												2041-1723					FEB 8	2019	10								668	10.1038/s41467-019-08503-8								WOS:000458175300017	30737392					
J	Cao, WY; Li, CT; Zhang, J; Dong, DF; Sun, XQ; Yao, SQ; Huang, BS; Liu, J				Cao, Wanyi; Li, Chuting; Zhang, Jing; Dong, Daifeng; Sun, Xiaoqiang; Yao, Shuqiao; Huang, Bingsheng; Liu, Jun			Regional Homogeneity Abnormalities in Early-Onset and Adolescent-Onset Conduct Disorder in Boys: A Resting-State fMRI Study	FRONTIERS IN HUMAN NEUROSCIENCE												Purpose: Developmental taxonomic theory posits that formation of early-onset conduct disorder (EO-CD), is considered to have a neurodevelopmental etiology and have more severe psychosocial and neuropsychological dysfunction than adolescent-onset CD (AO-CD), which is thought to stem largely from social mimicry of deviant peers. The purpose of the current study was to investigate whether regional homogeneity (ReHo), denoting the spontaneous brain activity, supports developmental taxonomic theory in a resting state (rs). Materials and Methods: Rs-functional magnetic resonance imaging (fMRI) examinations were administered to 36 EO-CD patients, 32 AO-CD patients, and 30 healthy controls (HCs). All participants were male adolescents, aged between 12 and 17 years old. A one-way analysis of covariance (ANCOVA), with age and IQ as covariates, was performed to identify regions with significant group differences in ReHo values, followed by a post hoc analyses. Results: Compared with the AO-CD groups, EO-CD had higher ReHo values in the right middle/inferior frontal gyrus. Compared with the HCs, the EO-CD group exhibited lower ReHo values in the left precuneus, left middle occipital gyrus, left cerebellum posterior lobe and the right inferior parietal lobule, as well as higher ReHo values in the right middle frontal gyrus, left insula/inferior frontal gyrus, right postcentral gyrus, and the left anterior cingulate gyrus. Compared with the HCs, the AO-CD group showed lower ReHo values in the bilateral precuneus, left cerebellum posterior lobe, and the right inferior parietal lobule. Conclusion: Significant differences in ReHo were observed between the EO-CD and AO-CD groups, implying distinct neuropathological mechanisms of the two CD subtypes, consistent with developmental taxonomic theory. CD-associated abnormalities in ReHo may be related to high-order cognitive and low-level perceptual system impairments in CD.																	1662-5161					FEB 7	2019	13								26	10.3389/fnhum.2019.00026								WOS:000458116500001						
J	Vanzella, P; Balardin, JB; Furucho, RA; Morais, GAZ; Janzen, TB; Sammler, D; Sato, JR				Vanzella, Patricia; Balardin, Joana B.; Furucho, Rogerio A.; Zimeo Morais, Guilherme Augusto; Janzen, Thenille Braun; Sammler, Daniela; Sato, Joao R.			fNIRS Responses in Professional Violinists While Playing Duets: Evidence for Distinct Leader and Follower Roles at the Brain Level	FRONTIERS IN PSYCHOLOGY												Music played in ensembles is a naturalistic model to study joint action and leader-follower relationships. Recently, the investigation of the brain underpinnings of joint musical actions has gained attention; however, the cerebral correlates underlying the roles of leader and follower in music performance remain elusive. The present study addressed this question by simultaneously measuring the hemodynamic correlates of functional neural activity elicited during naturalistic violin duet performance using fNIRS. Findings revealed distinct patterns of functional brain activation when musicians played the Violin 2 (follower) than the Violin 1 part (leader) in duets, both compared to solo performance. More specifically, results indicated that musicians playing the Violin 2 part had greater oxy-Hb activation in temporo-parietal (p = 0.02) and somatomotor (p = 0.04) regions during the duo condition in relation to the solo. On the other hand, there were no significant differences in the activation of these areas between duo/solo conditions during the execution of the Violin 1 part (p's > 0.05). These findings suggest that ensemble cohesion during a musical performance may impose particular demands when musicians play the follower position, especially in brain areas associated with the processing of dynamic social information and motor simulation. This study is the first to use fNIRS hyperscanning technology to simultaneously measure the brain activity of two musicians during naturalistic music ensemble performance, opening new avenues for the investigation of brain correlates underlying joint musical actions with multiple subjects in a naturalistic environment.																	1664-1078					FEB 5	2019	10								164	10.3389/fpsyg.2019.00164								WOS:000457847100001						
